Guide to the Morris Schappes Papers TAM.179
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Personal Papers, 1913-2003
  - Writings: Articles and Reprints - Jewish Currents (I), 1956-1982 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Writings: Articles and Reprints - Jewish Currents (II), 1947-1982 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Writings: Articles and Reprints - Jewish Life, 1938-1956 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Writings: Articles and Reprints - Morning Freiheit, 1943-1946, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Writings: Book Reviews, 1930-1937 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Writings: Book Reviews, 1938-1955, 1977, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Writings: "Caught Reading Shelley to My Students" from City at the Center, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Writings: "The Character of the American Press", undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Writings: "Educating Immigrants, Then and Now" (and Associated Correspondence), 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Writings: Emma Lazarus Articles from The American Hebrew, 1943, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Writings: "Excerpts from Robert Morris' 'Diaries in the Office of Finance, 1781-1784,' Referring to Haym Salomon and Other Jews", 1954, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Writings: "How American Writers Saw the Jews," Review of Louis Harap's "The Image of the Jew in American Literature", 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Writings: "Immigrant Education...Then and Now", 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Writings: "The Irrational Malady", 1930 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Writings: "Itzik Feffer: Soviet Jewish Poet" from The Chicago Jewish Forum, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Writings: "Jews in American History: A Teacher's Guide" - Correspondence and Clippings, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Writings: Letters to the Editor, Various, 1933-1989 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Writings: "Mr. Cronbach's Economic Quandry" from The Hebrew Union College Monthly, January 15, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Writings: Opening Remarks, Various, 1971-2000 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Writings: "Organizing Academic Freedom", 1936 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Writings: "Problems of Jewish Culture" from Masses & Mainstream, March 1950 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Writings: "Reflections on Old Age" and "Time Done", 1945, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Writings: "A Sketch of the History of the Broadening of the Concept of the People's Front in the United States", Undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Writings: "The Story of Three Hundred Years, 16 Chapters of American Jewish History", 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Writings: "Translate and Unite," Paper Presented at American Jewish Culture Conference, October 31-November 1, 1949, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Writings: "Treason on Park Avenue" from New York Teacher, June 1941 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Writings: Various, 1935-1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Writings: "William Ernest Henley's Principles of Criticism" and Associated Correspondence, 1931, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Workmen's Circle / Arbeter Ring: Schappes' Membership, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Honors: Borough of Manhattan proclamation, Jews for Racial and Economic Justice recognition, 1997, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 006, Folder 7)
- Series II: Jewish Currents Files, 1958-2004
  This series highlights the role Schappes played in the management of Jewish Currents, serving as its editor from 1958 until 2004. Its three subseries include minutes of the Editorial Board and Editorial Advisory Council, a large amount of correspondence and a variety of administrative files.
  - Subseries IIA: Minutes
    Minutes of the journal's Editorial Board and Editorial Advisory Council (1962-2002) form the initial Jewish Currents subseries.
    Folders are arranged chronologically within each organizational unit.
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, 1962, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Jan 1987-Jun 1987 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Jul 1987-Dec 1987 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Jan 1988-Jun 1988 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Jul 1988-Dec 1988 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Jan 1989-Apr 1989 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, May 1989-Aug 1989 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Sep 1989-Oct 1989 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Nov 1989-Dec 1989 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Jan 1990-Apr 1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, May 1990-Jul 1990 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Aug 1990-Dec 1990 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Jan 1997-Jun 1997 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Aug 1997-Dec 1997 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Jan 1998-Jun 1998 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Jul 1998-Dec 1998 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Jan 1999-Apr 1999 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, May 1999-Jul 1999 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Sep 1999-Dec 1999 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Jan 2000-Mar 2000 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Apr 2000-Jun 2000 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Jul 2000-Sep 2000 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Oct 2000-Dec 2000 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Jan 2001-Mar 2001 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Apr 2001-Aug 2001 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Sep 2001-Dec 2001 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Jan 2002-Jun 2002 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Minutes: Jewish Currents Editorial Board, Jul 2002-Dec 2002 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council, 1968-1972 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council, 1972-1975 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council, 1976-1978 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council, 1979-1982 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council, 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council, 2001-2002 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Editorial Advisory Conference / Council - Attendance Sheets, 1968-2002 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Minutes and Related Material: Shabbos Board, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Subseries IIB: Correspondence
    This subseries consists primarily of chronologically arranged letters (1952-2004) including many with attached submissions of stories, articles and poetry. There is also a large group of letters that Jewish Currents staff organized alphabetically by correspondent name. In addition, there are a number of special categories including rejection letters, Management Committee mailings and a few unusual types such as crank letters and letters containing death threats.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically, then in chronological order within category.
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, 1958-1969 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, 1980-1985 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, Jan 1998-Mar 1998 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, May 1998-Sep 1998 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, Oct 1998-Dec 1998 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, Jan 2000-Feb 2000 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, Mar 2000-Apr 2000 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, May 2000-Jun 2000 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, Jul 2000-Aug 2000 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, Sep 2000-Oct 2000 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, Nov 2000-Dec 2000 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, Jan 2001-Feb 2001 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, Mar 2001-Jun 2001 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, Jul 2001-Sep 2001 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, Oct 2001-Dec 2001 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, Jan 2002-Mar 2002 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, Apr 2002-May 2002 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, Jun 2002-Aug 2002 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, Sep 2002-Oct 2002 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, Nov 2002-Dec 2002 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence, 2003, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - A, 1985-1999 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Adler, David, 1995-1997 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Arnold, Abraham, 1991-1997 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Askin, Steve (Zimbabwe), 1986-1989 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Axelerad, Rabbi Albert, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - B (Ba-Be), 1984-1999 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - B (Bi-Bu), 1984-1999 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - B - Baert, Frederique, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - B - Bass, Claudette, 1991-1997, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - B - Berger, David, 1995-1998 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - B - Bluefarb, Sam, 1997-1999 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - B - Brumberg, Stephan, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - B - Buhle, Paul (Includes Essay, "Between the Universal and the Particular: Jewish Radicalism in the U.S., 1890-1940"), 1986-1999 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - C (Ca-Ch), 1984-1999 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - C (Ci-Cz), 1984-1999 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Chevat, Edith (re: E. M. Broner), 1999-2000 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - D, 1985-2000 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Dimow, Joseph and Lillian, 1987-1993 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Donohue, William A., 1998 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - E, 1985-2000 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Edelman, Joseph, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - F (Fa-Fi), 1985-1999 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - F (Fl-Fo), 1985-1999 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - F (Fr-Fu), 1985-1999 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Ferber, Irwin, 1986-1999 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Foner, Henry, 1986-1999 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - G (Ga-Gl), 1985-2000 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - G (Go), 1985-2000 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - G (Gr-Gu), 1985-2000 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Gordon, Eric, 1990-2000 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Gordon, Max and Midi, 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Graubart, Jonathan "Rethinking Anti-Semitism on the Left", 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - H (Ha-He), 1985-1998 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - H (Hi-Hy), 1985-1998 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Hartman, Hershl, 1994-1996 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Hecht, Mike (I), 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Hecht, Mike (II), 2001 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - I, 1985-1998 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Isler, Alan, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - J, 1986-1998 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - K (Ka), 1985-1999 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - K (Ke-Kl), 1985-1999 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - K (Ko-Ku), 1985-1999 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Kahn, Avram, 1988-1994 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - L (La-Le), 1985-1999 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - L (Li-Lu), 1985-1999 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Lazaris, Vladimir, 1996, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - M (Ma-Mc), 1986-1998 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - M (Me-My), 1986-1998 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Meeropol, Robert, 1991, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Michels, Tony, 1987-1996 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - N, 1987-1998 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Neumaier, John J., 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - O, 1986-1999 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - P (Pa-Pe), 1986-1999 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - P (Ph-Pu), 1986-1999 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Porter, Jack Nusan, 1971-2000 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Portnow, Billie, 1985-1991 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Prago, Albert, 1988-1993 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - R (Ra-Ri), 1985-1999 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - R (Rob-Rol), 1985-1999 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - R (Ros-Row), 1985-1999 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - R (Ru-Ry), 1985-1999 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Rubenstein, Annette, 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - S (Sa), 1981-2000 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - S (Sc-Se), 1985-2000 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - S (Sh-Sl), 1985-2000 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - S (Sm-Sw), 1985-2000 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Sabin, Arthur J., 1986-1993 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Seckar, Alvena, 1992-1999 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Seliger, Ralph, 1994-1997 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Slavin, Morris, 1990-1997 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Snitow, Virginia, 1993-2000 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - T, 1987-2000 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - U, 1987-1996 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - V, 1985-1999 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - W (Wa), 1985-1999 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - W (We), 1985-1999 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - W (Wh-Wy), 1985-1999 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Y, 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Alpha Files - Z, 1985-1999 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: "Convict Curiosities", 1993, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: "Crank", 1998-2002 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Death Threats from Goldwater Partisans, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Editorial Advisory Committee Letters, 1997-2004 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Exchange with Other Publications, 1975-2000 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Jewish Braille Institute, 1992-1993 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Management Committee Mailings, 1997-2004 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Rejection Letters with Submissions, 1991, 1979-1999 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Rejection Letters with Submissions, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Rejection Letters with Submissions, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Rejection Letters with Submissions, Jan 2002-Jun 2002 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Rejection Letters with Submissions, 2002-2003, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Rejection Letters without Submissions, 1996-1999 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Rejection Letters without Submissions, Feb 2000-Jul 2000 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Rejection Letters without Submissions, Aug 2000-Dec 2000 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Rejection Letters without Submissions, Jan 2001-Mar 2001 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Rejection Letters without Submissions, Apr 2001-Sep 2001 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Rejection Letters without Submissions, Oct 2001-Apr 2002 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Rejection Letters without Submissions, May 2002-Jan 2003 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Submissions, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Submissions, 1977-1979 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Submissions, 1980-1989 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Submissions, 1989-1990 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Submissions, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Submissions, 1992-1998 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Submissions, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Submissions, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Submissions, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Submissions, Jan 2002-Mar 2002 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Submissions, May 2002-Aug 2002 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Submissions, Sep 2002-Jan 2003 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Jewish Currents Correspondence: Submissions ("Shabbos in Brooklyn"), 2000-2002 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Subseries IIC: Administrative Files
    This subseries consists of administrative files, touching on many aspects of the magazine's existence such as events, advertising, layout and format, graphics, book review materials, reader questionnaires, drafts and proofs of many articles (including notes), and material associated with Schappes' column, "The Editor's Diary."
    Folders in this subseries are arranged alphabetically.
    - Advertisements, Memorials and Personals, 1995-2002 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Advertising Exchange, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Book Review Materials, 1958, 1983-1986 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Book Review Materials, 1986-1997 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Book Review Materials, 1996-1999 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Book Review Materials, 2000-2002, undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Book Review Materials: Notes, 1992-2002 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Book Reviewer Lists, 1997, undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Editorial Advisory Council, 1985-1994 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Editorial Advisory Council, 1995-1999 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Editorial Advisory Council, 2000-2002 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Format Materials, 1998-2002, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Fourth Jewish Currents Reader 1976-1986, 1985-1989 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Friends of Jewish Currents, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Funds / Expenses, 1989-2000 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Graphics, 1975-2001, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Graphics: Afro American History Caravan, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Graphics: Bilander, Jack, 2000, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Graphics: Cover Selection and Correspondence, 1989-2000 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Graphics: Dresher, Paul, 1997, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Graphics: Exhibition Catalogs and Prints, 1959-1988 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Graphics: Exhibition Catalogs and Prints, 1990-2002, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Graphics: Museum of Jewish Heritage, 1999-2000 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Graphics: Polish Papercuts, including CD (Skirball Cultural Center), 2001 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Graphics: "Yiddishland", 1999 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Hacker, David, " Jewish Currents--A History" (typescript), 2004 (Box 16, Folder 10a)